[Music]
hello everyone and welcome back to
five dollar shake in today's video is
all about our latest
homemade ice cream flavor the lemon
meringue
pie ice cream so we're going to get
stuck in and show you how you can make
this yourself at home
we will be posting the full recipe in
the description below as well
so to start off in a large mixing bowl
add two cups
or 500 ml of heavy cream if you're here
in the uk
it's double cream and in the same bowl
add in one cup of whole milk full fat
milk
which is about 250 mil
and after a little bit of
post-production magic
we have a clean scoop and
in goes three quarters of a cup of
granulated sugar
which is 170 grams
now this particular ice cream we have
gone for a philly style
base which is an eggless base
and it gives a gorgeous creamy luxurious
texture
adding now into the bowl is a half a
teaspoon
of vanilla extract
[Music]
the recipe for a standard philly base
does actually call for a full teaspoon
of vanilla extract
but because we're adding in some lemon
flavor in a moment
we've knocked that down to half a
teaspoon
now in with this we're going to be
adding in some non-fat powdered milk
uh nick we can't actually see what
you're holding up there
bring it a bit closer perfect
so this is going to be two tablespoons
of non-fat powdered milk which acts as a
stabilizer
to the ice cream to prevent it from
going rock solid in your freezer
[Music]
and now for the lemon element of this
ice cream base
where we're grating in a rind of one
fresh lemon
and this gives it a gorgeous subtle
fresh
lemony flavor to your base nothing too
overpowering
because we're going to step it up a
notch later on when we're assembling the
ice cream
into our container all that's left to do
now
is whisk all your ingredients together
nick proudly showing off his whisk give
it a good old stir to combine
please do check us out on our social
media accounts you'll find us on
instagram facebook tik tok we post
exclusive content
behind the scenes sneak peeks all kinds
of stuff so please do get involved
at this stage we've been chilling out
ice cream maker for around 10 minutes
so when your mixture is ready pour it
into your ice cream maker
and let it churn take about 30 minutes
depending on your
machine that you're using until you have
that beautiful
soft serve consistency and now all
that's left to do is assemble your ice
cream into your
pre-chilled container i'm going to be
layering up
the gorgeous lemon ice cream base
from your ice cream maker and then
adding in some meringue
and lemon curd so start off with a good
generous dollop
in the bottom of your container of your
ice cream
[Music]
then we're going to be mixing through
some crushed french
meringue and we will be honest we have
gone for the shop bought
meringue here we did make our own french
meringue couple of weeks ago for our
halloween video and made a lovely family
of meringue
ghosts but they didn't last very long in
this house
so we've had to resort to the shop
bought
on top of the meringue we're going for a
dollop of lemon curd again we have gone
for the shop
version here it is good stuff we usually
make our own
at home it's very easy to do
a combination of fresh lemon juice eggs
butter and sugar
but we'll blame laziness or time
constraints i'll have to explain the
lockdown
that's why we went for shot bought on
this occasion
[Music]
and keep layering up add more ice cream
cram in as much as that delicious
meringue and lemon curd as you can
if you are enjoying this video please do
like and subscribe to our channel
we will be making a lot of delicious
homemade ice creams for you going
forward
some classic flavors some possibly
weirder wonderful ones in there as well
we've got dairy free vegan recipes in
the making
some gorgeous christmas ones that we're
planning as well
so please do like and subscribe to keep
up to date with all our latest
videos and at the end of november we're
actually going to be using
this ice cream that we're making here
today in one of our
milkshakes so please do also look out
for that one it's going to be
amazing thank you very much for joining
us today
hope you join us for the next one